<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Tax updating</title>
    <link href="/2023/06/23/Tax/"/>
    <url>/2023/06/23/Tax/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="Individual-income-tax-rates"><a href="#Individual-income-tax-rates" class="headerlink" title="Individual income tax rates"></a>Individual income tax rates</h3><table><thead><tr><th>Taxable income</th><th>Tax on this income</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>0 – 18,200</td><td>Nil</td></tr><tr><td>18,201 – 45,000</td><td>19c for each $1 over 18,200</td></tr><tr><td>45,001 – 120,000</td><td>5,092 plus 32.5c for each $1 over 45,000</td></tr><tr><td>120,001 – 180,000</td><td>29,467 plus 37c for each $1 over 120,000</td></tr><tr><td>180,001 and over</td><td>51,667 plus 45c for each $1 over 180,000</td></tr></tbody></table><h3 id="Medicare-levy"><a href="#Medicare-levy" class="headerlink" title="Medicare levy"></a>Medicare levy</h3><p>The Medicare levy is an amount you pay in addition to the tax you pay on your taxable income.<br>The Medicare levy helps fund some of the costs of Australia’s public health system known as Medicare. The Medicare levy is 2% of your taxable income</p><h3 id="Assessable-income"><a href="#Assessable-income" class="headerlink" title="Assessable income"></a>Assessable income</h3><p>Most of the income you earn will be assessable income. Assessable income is income that you pay tax on, if you earn enough to exceed the tax-free threshold. Examples of assessable income you must declare include:</p><ul><li>salary and wages</li><li>tips, gratuities and other payments for your services</li><li>some allowances, such as for clothing and laundry</li><li>interest from bank accounts</li><li>dividends and other income from investments</li><li>bonuses and overtime an employee receives</li><li>commission a salesperson receives</li><li>pensions</li><li>rent.</li></ul><p>You may also receive some income in the form of goods or services instead of money. You need to declare the market value of these goods or services as assessable income in your tax return. For example, you may receive clothing, makeup, tools, or accessories from subscribers or fans of your online platforms, or businesses looking to work with you.</p><p>If you receive your income as cash including cash cheques, you must declare the cash as income in your tax return.</p><h3 id="Taxable-income"><a href="#Taxable-income" class="headerlink" title="Taxable income"></a>Taxable income</h3><p>Your taxable income is your assessable income minus any allowable deductions. Your taxable income is used to work out how much tax you need to pay.</p><p><strong>Assessable income − allowable deductions &#x3D; taxable income</strong></p><p>Allowable deductions don’t directly reduce the amount of tax you pay, they reduce your taxable income, which in turn reduces the amount of tax you need to pay</p><h3 id="Exempt-income-from-a-scholarship"><a href="#Exempt-income-from-a-scholarship" class="headerlink" title="Exempt income from a scholarship"></a>Exempt income from a scholarship</h3><p>For a scholarship payment to be exempt from paying tax, you must meet <strong>all</strong> of the following conditions:</p><ul><li>The payment can’t be an excluded government payment (for example, Austudy, Youth Allowance or ABSTUDY).</li><li>There is no <a href="https://www.ato.gov.au/individuals/income-deductions-offsets-and-records/income-you-must-declare/scholarships-prizes-and-awards/scholarship-payments/#Workrequirement">requirement for you to do work</a> (either as an employee or contract for labour, now or in the future).</li><li>You are a <a href="https://www.ato.gov.au/individuals/income-deductions-offsets-and-records/income-you-must-declare/scholarships-prizes-and-awards/scholarship-payments/#Fulltimestudentataschoolcollegeorunivers">full-time student at a school, college or university</a>.</li><li>The scholarship is provided to you principally for <a href="https://www.ato.gov.au/individuals/income-deductions-offsets-and-records/income-you-must-declare/scholarships-prizes-and-awards/scholarship-payments/#Educationalpurposes">educational purposes</a>.</li></ul><h2 id="Reference"><a href="#Reference" class="headerlink" title="Reference:"></a>Reference:</h2><p><a href="https://www.ato.gov.au/Individuals/Income-deductions-offsets-and-records/Income-you-must-declare/Taxable-assessable-and-exempt-income/?anchor=Taxableincome#Taxableincome">https://www.ato.gov.au/Individuals/Income-deductions-offsets-and-records/Income-you-must-declare/Taxable-assessable-and-exempt-income/?anchor=Taxableincome#Taxableincome</a><br><a href="https://www.ato.gov.au/individuals/income-deductions-offsets-and-records/income-you-must-declare/scholarships-prizes-and-awards/scholarship-payments/">https://www.ato.gov.au/individuals/income-deductions-offsets-and-records/income-you-must-declare/scholarships-prizes-and-awards/scholarship-payments/</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Finance</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Finance</tag>
      
      <tag>Term</tag>
      
      <tag>Tex</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Superannuation updating</title>
    <link href="/2023/06/23/Superannuation/"/>
    <url>/2023/06/23/Superannuation/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="What-is-super"><a href="#What-is-super" class="headerlink" title="What is super"></a>What is super</h2><p>Super is a long-term investment designed to to help you for your retirement. For most working Australians,  it’s compulsory for your employer to make contributions to your super on your behalf - these are called <strong>Superannuation Guarantee</strong> (SG) contributions. It’s also a tax-effective way to save for retirement.</p><h3 id="How-to-choose"><a href="#How-to-choose" class="headerlink" title="How to choose"></a>How to choose</h3><p>You can generally choose which super fund you would like your SG contributions paid into. Check with your employer or visit <a href="https://www.ato.gov.au/Individuals/Super">ATO website</a> for more information</p><h3 id="How-to-contribute"><a href="#How-to-contribute" class="headerlink" title="How to contribute"></a>How to contribute</h3><p>There are different types of super contributions, including employer contributions, personal contributions and government co-contributions (also called ‘super co-contributions’) Different types of contributions are taxed in different ways. There are caps on the amount you can contribute in a financial year. If you go over these caps you may have to pay extra tax</p><h4 id="Contributions-from-your-employer"><a href="#Contributions-from-your-employer" class="headerlink" title="Contributions from your employer"></a>Contributions from your employer</h4><p>Under current Superannuation Guarantee (SG) legislation, employers in Australia are generally required to contribute an amount to their employees’ super that’s equal to at least 10.5% of their wages or salary</p><p>SG contributions are usually taxed within the Fund at a rate of <strong>15%</strong> as they’re paid into your super account</p><h4 id="Contributions-from-yourself"><a href="#Contributions-from-yourself" class="headerlink" title="Contributions from yourself"></a>Contributions from yourself</h4><p>You can contribute more money to your super in several ways. The different types<br>of contributions generally fall into two categories: before-tax or after-tax</p><table><thead><tr><th></th><th>Before-tax contributions (also called concessional contributions)</th><th>After-tax contributions (also callednon-concessional contributions)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>What are they</td><td>Super contributions that have been made before your income tax has been calculated (up to the contribution cap of $27,500 a year), or, after-tax contributions for which you claim a tax deduction</td><td>Super contributions taken from your ‘take-home’ pay after income-tax has already been deducted (Up to the contributions cap of $110,000 a year, are tax-free)</td></tr><tr><td>When they’re taxed</td><td>Generally taxed at 15% when they’re received by your super fund</td><td>Generally not taxed when they’re received by your super fund</td></tr><tr><td>Examples</td><td>• Salary sacrifice contributions • Personal deductible contributions • Employer SG contributions</td><td>• Personal after-tax contributions • Spouse contributions</td></tr></tbody></table><h4 id="Government-co-contributions"><a href="#Government-co-contributions" class="headerlink" title="Government co-contributions"></a>Government co-contributions</h4><p>Government co-contributions (also known as ‘super co-contributions’) are designed to help people on lower incomes boost their super savings. To qualify, you need to make a personal<br>after-tax contribution to your super before the end of the financial year</p><p>Then, providing you meet the other eligibility requirements, the government will contribute an additional 0.50 to your super for every dollar of after-tax contribution you’ve made up to a maximum co-contribution amount of $500</p><h4 id="Spouse-contributions"><a href="#Spouse-contributions" class="headerlink" title="Spouse contributions"></a>Spouse contributions</h4><p>Your spouse may be able to make an after-tax contribution into your super account on your behalf, subject to eligibility requirements. Any spouse contributions made into your account count towards the non-concessional (after-tax) contribution cap.</p><p>Spouse contributions made on behalf of a low-income spouse may be eligible for a tax offset of up to $540. This is why spouse contributions are sometimes used by couples as a way to help reduce the tax they pay</p><h3 id="First-Home-Super-Saver-Scheme"><a href="#First-Home-Super-Saver-Scheme" class="headerlink" title="First Home Super Saver Scheme"></a>First Home Super Saver Scheme</h3><p>The First Home Super Saver Scheme (FHSS Scheme) is a government scheme intended to help first home buyers save money for their first home within their super fund. You can make personal deductible (before tax) and personal after-tax contributions into your super fund to save for your first home. You can then apply to release these personal contributions, along with associated earnings, to help you purchase your first home. You can apply to have a maximum of 15,000 of your personal after-tax contributions from any one financial year included in your eligible contributions to be released under the FHSS Scheme, up to a total of $50,000 contributions across all years. You’ll also receive the earnings on those contributions.</p><h2 id="Accessing-your-super"><a href="#Accessing-your-super" class="headerlink" title="Accessing your super"></a>Accessing your super</h2><h3 id="When-you-can-access-your-super"><a href="#When-you-can-access-your-super" class="headerlink" title="When you can access your super"></a>When you can access your super</h3><p>• You retire permanently from the workforce on or after reaching your preservation age<br>• You reach your preservation age and start a transition to retirement income stream<br>• You leave paid employment on or after reaching age 60<br>• You reach age 65 (even if you’re still working).</p><p>1 July 1964 or later the preservation age is 60</p><h3 id="If-you-leave-Australia"><a href="#If-you-leave-Australia" class="headerlink" title="If you leave Australia"></a>If you leave Australia</h3><p>If you’ve worked in Australia as a temporary resident, you may be able to claim your super under the government’s departing Australia superannuation payment scheme once you depart Australia. Your temporary visa must have expired (or have been cancelled), and you must have left Australia permanently (taxed at 35%). </p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Finance</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Finance</tag>
      
      <tag>Term</tag>
      
      <tag>Super</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>How to invest Updating</title>
    <link href="/2023/06/06/How%20to%20invest/"/>
    <url>/2023/06/06/How%20to%20invest/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="Golden-rules-of-investing"><a href="#Golden-rules-of-investing" class="headerlink" title="Golden rules of investing"></a>Golden rules of investing</h3><ul><li>Pay off your debts first — pay off any loans</li><li>Have emergency savings — at least cover three months’ expenses</li><li>Develop an investing plan — define your financial goals, risk tolerance and investment time frame</li><li>Research different asset classes — understand the risks and returns</li><li>Diversify your investments — spread your money across and within asset classes to lower the portfolio’s risk</li><li>Keep track of investments — review them regularly</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Finance</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Finance</tag>
      
      <tag>Invest</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Financial Term Updating</title>
    <link href="/2023/06/02/Financial%20Term/"/>
    <url>/2023/06/02/Financial%20Term/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4 id="CFD"><a href="#CFD" class="headerlink" title="CFD"></a>CFD</h4><p>CFD stands for “Contract for Difference.” CFDs are financial derivatives that allow traders to speculate on the price movements of various financial instruments, such as stocks, commodities, indices, or currencies, without actually owning the underlying asset</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Finance</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Finance</tag>
      
      <tag>Term</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Australia Brokers updating</title>
    <link href="/2023/06/02/Australia%20Brokers/"/>
    <url>/2023/06/02/Australia%20Brokers/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Things-to-know-before-choosing-Brokers"><a href="#Things-to-know-before-choosing-Brokers" class="headerlink" title="Things to know before choosing Brokers"></a>Things to know before choosing Brokers</h2><p>Before choose which Brokers app you will use. You must understand what kind of trader you are.</p><h3 id="What’s-your-trading-style"><a href="#What’s-your-trading-style" class="headerlink" title="What’s your trading style?"></a>What’s your trading style?</h3><p>There are three types of trading styles.</p><h4 id="Casual-traders"><a href="#Casual-traders" class="headerlink" title="Casual traders"></a>Casual traders</h4><p>If you buy or sell shares once or twice a month (or even less), you’re a casual investor. You may want to avoid brokers that have an inactivity fee or charge higher broker fees for less frequent trades.</p><h4 id="Active-traders"><a href="#Active-traders" class="headerlink" title="Active traders"></a>Active traders</h4><p>If you intend to buy and sell shares multiple times in a day, you’re an active trader. You’d want to look for platforms that offer low brokerage for high-frequency trading and an extensive range of trading features, such as charting tools and order options</p><h4 id="Long-term-investors"><a href="#Long-term-investors" class="headerlink" title="Long-term investors"></a>Long-term investors</h4><p>Investors use the “buy and hold” strategy by targeting quality companies they think will rise over a long time frame and possibly offer dividends. They may only buy and sell a few times in a year. Investors may find the inactivity fee more important than a stock analysis feature.</p><h3 id="How-to-compare-online-brokers"><a href="#How-to-compare-online-brokers" class="headerlink" title="How to compare online brokers"></a>How to compare online brokers</h3><p>Here are some of the key features to look at when comparing online share trading platforms:</p><ul><li><strong>The broker fees.</strong> Almost every online trading platform will charge you a brokerage fee (also called a <strong>commission fee</strong>) when you buy or sell shares, ranging from around $10 to $30 per trade. These fees may be calculated as a percentage of the transaction amount for larger trades and may also be lower depending on how frequently you trade.</li><li><strong>Monthly fees.</strong> Some providers charge ongoing subscription or inactivity fees where you’re charged if you make too few trades. This will especially be the case where a platform offers an extensive range of features for advanced traders.</li><li><strong>What can you trade?</strong> Some trading platforms will not only give you access to Australian shares but also international shares. Others will also allow you to trade currencies, indices and much more, so look for this functionality if it’s important to you.</li><li><strong>Ease of use.</strong> Share market trading can be complicated and often requires you to respond quickly to market changes. With this in mind, look for a platform that allows you to make fast and precise trades with minimum fuss.</li><li><strong>Access to market data.</strong> Does the platform offer dynamic, real-time or delayed market updates? Some platforms offer research and broker analysis on individual stocks that can come in handy.</li><li><strong>Order types.</strong> Consider the options available when you’re buying or selling shares. Can you place orders at market and&#x2F;or at limit and are other order types such as stop&#x2F;loss orders an option to add more flexibility to your trading?</li><li><strong>Reporting.</strong> Check what reporting tools each platform offers to help you track how your trades are performing, record dividends and pass on any relevant information to the ATO at tax time.</li><li><strong>Customer support.</strong> Look for phone, email and live online chat support. Does it offer customer service 24&#x2F;7 if you’re having trouble placing a trade?</li><li><strong>Education.</strong> Some platforms also feature a range of educational tools and resources, such as how-to guides and webinars, to help you get more out of your trading account.</li><li><strong>Security.</strong> How secure is the platform and what measures are in place to ensure the safety of your funds?</li></ul><h3 id="What-fees-will-I-pay-to-trade"><a href="#What-fees-will-I-pay-to-trade" class="headerlink" title="What fees will I pay to trade"></a>What fees will I pay to trade</h3><p>Remember that many brokers offer different membership levels – for example, gold, silver and platinum – which offer different features and therefore attract varying fees.</p><ul><li><strong>Brokerage fees.</strong> Brokerage fees (also called commission fees) are the charges that apply to each buy and sell transaction of stocks and ETFs. They usually vary depending on the size of your buy or sell order or how often you trade.</li><li><strong>Ongoing fees.</strong> These apply monthly or annually, but not all providers will charge ongoing fees. This may depend on how frequently you trade, for example, inactivity fees are often charged if you don’t place any trades within a certain period of time.</li><li><strong>Withdrawal fees.</strong> Some brokers charge a fee to withdraw money from your account.</li><li><strong>Foreign exchange fees.</strong> If you want to buy US or other global shares, you’ll need to pay an exchange fee when you deposit money into your account to convert your Australian dollars to the applicable currency.</li></ul><h2 id="Australia-online-Brokers"><a href="#Australia-online-Brokers" class="headerlink" title="Australia online Brokers"></a>Australia online Brokers</h2><p><img src="/img/CMC.webp" alt="CMC Invest"></p><table><thead><tr><th>Feature</th><th>CMC Invest</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>ASX Trades (Up to $1000)</td><td><strong>$0</strong> Limited to one buy order per day</td></tr><tr><td>International Trades</td><td><strong>$0</strong> in US, UK, JAP and CAD</td></tr><tr><td>Inactivity&#x2F;Holding Fees</td><td><strong>$0</strong></td></tr><tr><td>International Markets</td><td>15 International markets</td></tr></tbody></table><table><thead><tr><th>Feature</th><th>Standard</th><th>Alpha</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>ASX Trades (Up to $1000 per day)</td><td><strong>$0</strong></td><td><strong>$0</strong></td></tr><tr><td>Other buy orders</td><td>$11 or 0.10%</td><td>$9.9 or 0.075%</td></tr><tr><td>All sell orders</td><td>$11 or 0.10%</td><td>$9.9 or 0.075%</td></tr></tbody></table><hr><p><img src="/img/Superhero.webp" alt="Superhero"></p><table><thead><tr><th>Feature</th><th>Superhero</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Trading Account Brokerage (ASX)</td><td>No Charge on ETF purchases  A$5.00 flat fee on all other trades including the sale of ETFs</td></tr><tr><td>Trading Account Fees</td><td>No Charge</td></tr><tr><td>Minimum Trade Size</td><td>A$100</td></tr><tr><td>Bank Transfer Deposit Fee</td><td>No Charge Deposit into your Superhero Account&#x2F;BSB</td></tr></tbody></table><hr><p><img src="/img/CommSec.png" alt="CommSec"></p><h2 id="Reference"><a href="#Reference" class="headerlink" title="Reference:"></a>Reference:</h2><ol><li><a href="https://www.cmcmarkets.com/en-au/legal-documents/stockbroking-legal-documents">CMC</a></li><li><a href="https://www.superhero.com.au/support/#second">Superhero</a></li><li><a href="https://www.commsec.com.au/content/dam/EN/PDFs/FSG/fsg.pdf">CommSec</a></li><li><a href="https://www.moomoo.com/au/pricing">Moomoo</a></li><li><a href="https://pearler.com/financial-services-guide">Pearler</a></li></ol>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Finance</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Finance</tag>
      
      <tag>Broker</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>MATLAB Cheat Sheet updating</title>
    <link href="/2023/04/28/MATLAB%20Cheat%20Sheet/"/>
    <url>/2023/04/28/MATLAB%20Cheat%20Sheet/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Basic-commands"><a href="#Basic-commands" class="headerlink" title="Basic commands"></a>Basic commands</h2><table><thead><tr><th>Commands</th><th>Description</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><code>clc</code></td><td>Clear command window</td></tr><tr><td><code>clear</code></td><td>Clear system memory</td></tr><tr><td><code>clear x</code></td><td>Clear x from memory</td></tr><tr><td><code>doc normally distributed numbers</code></td><td>Searching the documentation for a function that creates normally distributed numbers</td></tr></tbody></table><h2 id="Standard-Matrix-and-vector-operations"><a href="#Standard-Matrix-and-vector-operations" class="headerlink" title="Standard Matrix and vector operations"></a>Standard Matrix and vector operations</h2><table><thead><tr><th>Commands</th><th>Description</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><code>x = [1, 2, 3]</code> or <code>x=[1 2 3]</code></td><td>1x3 (Row) vector defined</td></tr><tr><td><code>x = [1; 2; 3]</code></td><td>3x1 (Column) vector defined</td></tr><tr><td><code>x = [1, 2, 3; 4, 5, 6; 7, 8, 9]</code></td><td>3x3 matrix defined</td></tr><tr><td><code>x = 1:3</code> or <code>x = 1:1:3</code></td><td>1x3 (Row) vector defined</td></tr><tr><td><code>x = linspace(1,3,3)</code></td><td>function to create vector <code>linspace(_first_,_last_,_number_of_elements_)</code></td></tr><tr><td><code>x = x&#39;</code></td><td>Transpose <code>x</code> from a row vector to a column vector using the transpose operator <code>&#39;</code></td></tr><tr><td><code>x = rand(3,3)</code> or <code>x = ones(3,3)</code> or <code>x = zeros(3,3)</code></td><td>Create a 3-by-3 matrix with (random, one, zero) numbers</td></tr><tr><td><code>size(x)</code></td><td>Get Rows and Columns</td></tr><tr><td><code>x(1,:)</code></td><td>Get first row of <code>x</code> matrix</td></tr><tr><td><code>x(:,1)</code></td><td>Get first colum of <code>x</code> matrix</td></tr><tr><td><code>x(end-1,1)</code></td><td>Get the second last row and 1st column</td></tr><tr><td><code>A = [5 6; 7 8]</code> <code>A(3)</code></td><td>If you use only one index with a matrix, MATLAB traverses down each column in order (this code returns the value <code>6</code>)</td></tr><tr><td><code>density([1 3 6])</code></td><td>Indices can be nonconsecutive numbers to extract the first, third, and sixth elements of <code>density</code></td></tr></tbody></table><h2 id="Operators"><a href="#Operators" class="headerlink" title="Operators"></a>Operators</h2><table><thead><tr><th>Operator</th><th>Purpose</th><th>Description</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td><code>+</code></td><td>Addition</td><td><code>A+B</code> adds <code>A</code> and <code>B</code></td></tr><tr><td><code>+</code></td><td>Unary plus</td><td><code>+A</code> rutruns <code>A</code></td></tr><tr><td><code>-</code></td><td>Subtraction</td><td><code>A-B</code> subtracts <code>B</code> from <code>A</code></td></tr><tr><td><code>-</code></td><td>Unary minus</td><td><code>-A</code> negates the elements of <code>A</code></td></tr><tr><td><code>.*</code></td><td>Element-wise multiplication</td><td><code>A.*B</code> is the element-by-element product of <code>A</code> and <code>B</code>.</td></tr><tr><td><code>.^</code></td><td>Element-wise power</td><td><code>A.^B</code> is the matrix with elements <code>A(i,j)</code> to the <code>B(i,j)</code> power.</td></tr><tr><td><code>./</code></td><td>Right array division</td><td><code>A./B</code> is the matrix with elements <code>A(i,j)/B(i,j)</code>.</td></tr><tr><td><code>.\</code></td><td>Left array division</td><td><code>A.\B</code> is the matrix with elements <code>B(i,j)/A(i,j)</code>.</td></tr><tr><td><code>.&#39;</code></td><td>Array transpose</td><td><code>A.&#39;</code> is the array transpose of <code>A</code>. For complex matrices, this does not involve conjugation.</td></tr><tr><td><code>~</code></td><td>Ignore output from a function</td><td><code>[~,ivMax] = max(v2)</code> <code>~</code> ignore the first output from <code>max()</code> function</td></tr></tbody></table>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>MATLAB</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>MATLAB</tag>
      
      <tag>Cheat Sheet</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Model-Based Reinforcement Learning: A Survey</title>
    <link href="/2022/06/26/model-based%20reinforcement%20learning/"/>
    <url>/2022/06/26/model-based%20reinforcement%20learning/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This blog is my brief summary about this survery paper. <sup id="fnref:1" class="footnote-ref"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote"><span class="hint--top hint--rounded" aria-label="Moerland, T. M., Broekens, J., Plaat, A., & Jonker, C. M. (2022). Model-based Reinforcement Learning: A Survey (No. arXiv:2006.16712). arXiv. doi: 10.48550/arXiv.2006.16712">[1]</span></a></sup></p><h3 id="Introduction"><a href="#Introduction" class="headerlink" title="Introduction"></a>Introduction</h3><p><img src="/img/Planning-and-Learning.png"><br><strong>The above figure shows an overview of possible algorithmic connections between planning and learning.</strong> </p><ul><li>(a) plan over a learned model</li><li>(b) use information from a policy&#x2F;value function to improve planning</li><li>(c) use the result from planning to train the policy&#x2F;value function</li><li>(d) act in the environment based on the planning outcome</li><li>(e) act in the environment based on policy&#x2F;value function</li><li>(f) train the policy&#x2F;value function based on experience</li><li>(g) train the model based on experience</li></ul><h4 id="Concepts"><a href="#Concepts" class="headerlink" title="Concepts"></a>Concepts</h4><p><em>Reversible access</em> the MDP dynamics is repeatedly planning forward from the same state (Planning methods, humans plan in their mind).</p><p><em>Irreversible access</em> to the MDP means that the agents has to move forward from the resulting next state after executing a particular action. (Model-free methods, human act in the real world)</p><p><em>Model</em> is a form of reverisble access to the MDP dynamics (known or learned)</p><p><em>Local solution</em> only stores the solution for a subset of all states. (Planning method)</p><p><em>Global solution</em> stores the value&#x2F;policy function for the entire state space. (Learning method)</p><p><em>Planning</em> is a class of MDP algorithms that 1) use a model and 2) store a local solution. </p><p><em>Reinforcement learning</em> is a class of MDP algorithms that store a global solution.</p><p><em>Model-based reinforcement learning</em> is a class of MDP algorithms that 1) use a model, and 2) store a global solution.</p><h3 id="Categories-of-planning-learning-integration"><a href="#Categories-of-planning-learning-integration" class="headerlink" title="Categories of planning-learning integration"></a>Categories of planning-learning integration</h3><ul><li>Model-based RL with a learned model, where we both learn a model and learn a global solution. (Dyna)</li><li>Model-based RL with a known model, where we plan over a known model, and only use learning for the global solution. (AlphaZero, Dynamic Programming)</li><li>Planning over a learned model, where we do learn a model, but subsequently locally plan over it, without learning a global solution.</li></ul><h3 id="Dynamics-Model-Learning"><a href="#Dynamics-Model-Learning" class="headerlink" title="Dynamics Model Learning"></a>Dynamics Model Learning</h3><p>Model learning is essentially a supervised learning problem<br><em>Dynamics models</em> is to learn the transition probabilities between states.</p><h4 id="Type-of-model"><a href="#Type-of-model" class="headerlink" title="Type of model"></a>Type of model</h4><ul><li>Forward model: $(s_t,a_t)\rightarrow s_{t+1}$<br>  Most commeon model can be used for lookahead planning.</li><li>Backward&#x2F;revers model: $s_{t+1}\rightarrow (s_t,a_t)$<br> Plan in the backwards direcion (Prioritized sweeping)</li><li>Inverse model: $(s_t,s_{t+1})\rightarrow a_t$<br>  Useful in representation learning (RRT planning)</li></ul><h4 id="Type-of-approximation-method"><a href="#Type-of-approximation-method" class="headerlink" title="Type of approximation method"></a>Type of approximation method</h4><ul><li><em>Parametric</em>: The number of parameters is independent of the size of the observed dataset.<ul><li><em>Exact</em>: For a discrete MDP (or a discretized version of a continuous MDP), a tabular method maintains a separate entry for every possible transition. However, they don not scale to high-dimensional problems (the curse of dimensionlity)<ul><li>Tabular maximum likelihood model<br>  $$T(s^\prime|s,a) &#x3D; \frac{n(s,a,s^\prime)}{\sum_{s^\prime} n(s,a,s^\prime)}$$</li></ul></li><li><em>Approximate</em>: Function approximation methods lower the required number of parameters and allow for generalization. <ul><li>Linear Regression</li><li>Dynamic Bayesian networks (DBN)</li><li>Nearst Neighbours</li><li>Random forests</li><li>Support vector regression</li><li>Neural Networks</li></ul></li></ul></li><li><em>Non-parametric</em>: Directly store and use the data to represent the model. And the computational complexity of non-parametric methods depends on the size of the dataset. So less applicable to high-dimension problems where normal require more data<ul><li><em>Exact</em>: Replay buffers</li><li><em>Approximate</em>: Gaussian processes</li></ul></li></ul><h4 id="The-region-of-state-space"><a href="#The-region-of-state-space" class="headerlink" title="The region of state space"></a>The region of state space</h4><ul><li>Global: Approcimate the dynamics over the entire state space. (Main approach)</li><li>Local: Locally approximate the dynamics and discard the local model after  planning over it.</li></ul><h3 id="Reference"><a href="#Reference" class="headerlink" title="Reference:"></a>Reference:</h3><section class="footnotes"><div class="footnote-list"><ol><li><span id="fn:1" class="footnote-text"><span>Moerland, T. M., Broekens, J., Plaat, A., &amp; Jonker, C. M. (2022). Model-based Reinforcement Learning: A Survey (No. arXiv:2006.16712). arXiv. doi: 10.48550&#x2F;arXiv.2006.16712<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote" class="footnote-backref"> ↩</a></span></span></li></ol></div></section>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Reinforcement Learning</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Model-Based</tag>
      
      <tag>RL</tag>
      
      <tag>Paper</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="/2022/06/25/hello-world/"/>
    <url>/2022/06/25/hello-world/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to <a href="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</a>! This is your very first post. Check <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/">documentation</a> for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html">troubleshooting</a> or you can ask me on <a href="https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues">GitHub</a>.</p><h2 id="Quick-Start"><a href="#Quick-Start" class="headerlink" title="Quick Start"></a>Quick Start</h2><h3 id="Create-a-new-post"><a href="#Create-a-new-post" class="headerlink" title="Create a new post"></a>Create a new post</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo new <span class="hljs-string">&quot;My New Post&quot;</span><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>OR simply</p><p>Create a new markdowm file in the _posts folder.</p><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/writing.html">Writing</a></p><h3 id="Run-server"><a href="#Run-server" class="headerlink" title="Run server"></a>Run server</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo server<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/server.html">Server</a></p><h3 id="Generate-static-files"><a href="#Generate-static-files" class="headerlink" title="Generate static files"></a>Generate static files</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo generate<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/generating.html">Generating</a></p><h3 id="Deploy-to-remote-sites"><a href="#Deploy-to-remote-sites" class="headerlink" title="Deploy to remote sites"></a>Deploy to remote sites</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo deploy<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/one-command-deployment.html">Deployment</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
